# Alberto Orlando Cime Castellanos



**Information Technology Engineer** 

#### Contact

#### Address:

C 32, 532 x 21 y 23 Salvador Alvarado Oriente Mérida, Yucatán, México

#### Phone:

+52 (999)1-74-51-54

#### **Email:**

Orland 998@hotmail.com

#### Date of birth:

June 6th, 1998

# Languages

Spanish – Native Language English – B2

# **Summary**

Jr Web Developer specializing in Backend development and cybersecurity. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for projects. Well-versed in programming languages including HTML5, PHP OOP, Node JS, applications pen testing and one year experience on AWS cloud. Strong background in project management and customer relations.

# **Hards Skills**

- Experience in Scrum Methodology
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused

#### **Softs Skills**

- Work team
- Responsible
- Dedicated

- Creative
- Friendly
- Studious

# **Experience**

# May 2021 to present – Fundación Rafael Dondé IAP Position: Jr. Technological Security Analist

- Implementation of basic controls in security architecture based on the AWS cloud, for the development of banking applications.
- Creation of VPCs, creation of public and private networks,
   Nat Gateways, entry and exit rules in security groups and privatization of network traffic on AWS cloud.
- Implementation of basic security controls, focused on secure development
- Creation and implementation of compensatory controls in cybersecurity.
- Best practices in the AWS IAM service, for managing access, policies, and groups
- creation of site-to-site VPN tunnels from the AWS cloud to on-premises servers.
- Using and configuring the WAF on AWS

# **Experience**

- Petesting web applications using the OWASP TOP 10 methodology and using tools such as ZAP proxy, sql map and Nmap.
- Basic use of Microsoft Active Directory.
- Basic use of Office 365 Exchange online.
- Use of service now to track tickets.
- Use of AWS lambda.
- Use of Terraform for the creation of infrastructure as code, such as the VPC in AWS.
- Use of AWS API Gateway
- Use of AWS Cognito
- Basic use of powershell
- Use of the AWS Secret Manager for key backup
- Intermediate-advanced use of the Postman tool
- Use of bitbucket for version control
- Perimeter security experience using the Fortinet firewall to:
  - o Policy creation
  - VPN creation
  - Creation of web filters
  - Navigation policies
  - Network traffic history tracking
  - Creation of network interfaces

#### November 2020 to April 2021 – Servicios e instalaciones Reyes

**Position:** Jr. Backend Developer

- Creation of Rest Api's using NodeJs and Express
- Using JWT for authentication
- Using the MVC Design Pattern
- Creation of microservices
- Intermediate-advanced use of the Postman tool
- Basic knowledge of Typescript
- Basic use of React for creating interfaces
- CSS and HTML for creating components in React
- Basic use of Ant-design
- Use MongoDB
- API RestFull implementation on AWS cloud

# **Experience**

### June 2020 to November 2020 - Universidad Tecnológica Metropolitana

Position: Jr. Backend Developer

- Creation of Rest Api's using NodeJs and Express
- Using JWT for authentication
- Using the MVC Design Pattern
- Use MongoDB
- Use of Canary Tokens

# March 2019 to Septembre 2019 – Secretaría Técnica de Planeación y evaluación (SEPLAN)

**Position:** Jr PHP Developer

- Creation API's using CodeIgniter Framework
- Inputs validations
- Use Bootstrap
- Use basic HTML and CSS

# **Acknowledge**

- Recognition for creditor fact to one of the best averages
- Degree by project
- General average 95.00

# **Education**

- Information Technology Engineer: Generation 2017-2021
- Universidad Tecnológica Metropolitana, Mérida, Yucatán, México

# **Certifications**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, PHP OOP, CSS, MySQL
- Frameworks: NodeJS, Express, CodeIgniter, Ant-Design, Bootstrap
- Cloud: AWS certification Solutions Architect (In progress)
- Networking: Cisco CCNA